<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on Clint Berry</title><link>https://clintberry.com/categories/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on Clint Berry</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://clintberry.com/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speed Up Your WordPress Development Cycle With Git</title><link>https://clintberry.com/2011/speed-up-your-wordpress-development-cycle-with-git/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clintberry.com/2011/speed-up-your-wordpress-development-cycle-with-git/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you have developed WordPress sites for clients this process might sound familiar to you:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Get a new client that wants a wordpress site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Download the most recent wordpress&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Find a good current blank wordpress theme to start implementing the design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upload to a staging server to for client to see&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Client requests changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You make changes on local server, then upload to staging server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repeat last three steps until finished and then you deploy the site to live&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After lots of trial and error, I have come up with a process that is more efficient, and allows rapid development of wordpress sites. I use Git, Git Submodules, and WordPress child themes to get going quicker and keep code up to date with minimal effort. (If your not using a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Revision_control" target="_blank">revision control &lt;/a>system like &lt;a href="http://git-scm.com/" target="_blank">Git&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/" target="_blank">SVN&lt;/a> for development, then check out &lt;del datetime="2012-04-22T20:33:39+00:00">&lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/132520/good-excuses-not-to-use-version-control" target="_blank">this funny question and answer session on Stack Overflow&lt;/a>&lt;/del> &lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> Stack Overflow moderators removed the question… bummer. Check out the funny-ness in the &lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20100722082534/http://stackoverflow.com/questions/132520/good-excuses-not-to-use-version-control" title="Why to use version control" target="_blank">wayback machine internet archiver&lt;/a> instead)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zend Studio and Git(Hub)</title><link>https://clintberry.com/2011/zend-studio-and-github/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://clintberry.com/2011/zend-studio-and-github/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been using Zend Studio as my IDE for years, and for version control I have always used SVN. Zend Studio Eclipse plays very nicely with SVN out of the box, but lately it seems Git has gained a lot of momentum so I thought I would look into it. It turns out Git is awesome and is much better suited for many of the things I do. (See: &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/871/why-is-git-better-than-subversion">Why Git?&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But will Git play nicely with Zend Studio 8?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to eclipse plugins, you bet it will!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>